Hello, you are very welcome,
I am Sandeep Grover with you on Mana and we are
trying to present such shares in front of you in
which there is a lot of movement, action, either they are
moving a lot or they are falling, there is a
decline in them, volume is being
seen, we are trying to
present all such trending shares in front of you
and in this series, the
share which we want to present before you
is ICICI Lombard General Insurance,
today the share of ICICI Lombard General Insurance has reached a record high, an up move of
to 7, we have
seen in the early trading today, the
record high of ₹1,766.95 paise has been
touched by the share of ICICI Lombard today,
till now if you see YTD, that is, in this year the
share has gone more than 20 and if you
see in the last 1 year also, the
performance of the share has been seen to be very strong,
in the last 1 year this share has
shown an up move of more than 45 and in the up move
seen today from 6 to 7, this  The
stock has seen record high
levels of around ₹1.66. So let's
try to understand the reason behind the rally.
Why does it have so much
potential?
Why has the stock risen so much in a year? There are
two or three reasons why the stock is
seeing action. Firstly, the premium numbers of
general insurance companies in May were
reported to be around 15%.
Overall, if you talk about this general insurance space, there has been a
growth in their premiums. The
premium figure that has
come in is
2098 crores. If
you talk about the sector, there has been good growth. The
premium collection in the month of May was around ₹8
crores. And
if you talk about health insurance premiums, then at the
overall industry level, the
total premium collection has seen a growth of around 26%. So, even
more support has been
seen in the companies of this entire space.
Secondly, if we look at the company's
numbers, the growth in May was
21.6%. The
company collected a premium of 20,015 crore in May, which has
generated a lot of excitement in the market. Therefore, we are seeing
very good action in the stock. While there has been
premium growth,
if you look at its market share,
it has also seen an increase of
60 basis points.
Its market share in May has seen a
growth of 6 basis points. On the
basis of this, we have seen a major block
deal taking place today. A deal of 2 million shares was seen taking place
in this stock today.
Because the numbers are very promising, the
premium growth was quite
good. Along with that, the
increased market share has
shown increased confidence in the market, which is why
we have also seen block deals today. In
fact, if you look at the confidence of some big investors and
promoters, they are continuously increasing.  This
company seems to be growing. Let us
try to present some figures before you to show
how the promoters and investors have
increased their stake. On May 9th, we saw a major
block deal taking place
in the shares of ISI Lombard, in which ISI Bank,
its promoter, bought 2.1 million
shares. They had
bought 4 shares from it. After the block deal on May 9th,
we saw an increase in ISI Bank's share. It was at 51.27 and then
it increased to 51.6. So the
promoters are continuously increasing their stake in it. In the
block deal that took place on May 9th,
buying was seen not only from ISI Bank but also from Morgan Stanley Asia Axis Mutual Fund and Investco Mutual Fund. Apart from this, some other
fund houses, including IIT Berla Sunlife
Mutual Fund, Societe Generale and
Goldman Sachs Singapore, buying was also seen from them in the
block deal that took place on May 9th. So, the
promoters are definitely
increasing their stake. Whenever a
big investor sells or exits
or reduces their stake here,  If it does,
promoters are coming forward and buying. Along with
that, the arrival of big names
like Morgan Snally and Goldman Sachs has
also given the market
confidence, which is why the stock
is continuously moving upwards and has delivered good returns of over 20% this year.
Even before this, if you look at this,
ICICI Bank has been continuously buying shares. On
February 27, the bank bought 8.1 million shares,
increasing its stake by around 2/4ths.
After that, if you look at it two days later, on
February 29, the bank again bought around 2.4 million
shares, of which
around ₹4,431 crore was bought by ICICI Bank.
Why is this happening?
In May 2023, ICICI Bank
passed a resolution. Its board
approved that it would increase its total stake in ICICI Lombard by
4% in multiple tranches,
which is why we are watching.
ICICI Bank has also bought into Indian Enterprises, which recently sold its stake.
This happened in May.
Before that, in February also,
they had bought a large stake
in ISI Lombard in two tranches. Whenever
a promoter increases its stake in a company, it is
seen as a confidence booster. Along with that, the
entry of big investors and the kind
of premium growth numbers this company is
reporting shows
why the promoter is bullish on this company.
Because the business performance of this company is
very solid, due to which today the
share of ICICI Bank has touched a record high. There are
many such stocks in
which strong action was seen today. We will
try to bring more videos on different stocks in which today either up
move or down move was seen which
stocks are trending. Thank you very much
for watching. Hello
[appreciation]